Inventory of the Media Collection, 1928 - [ongoing]
Media Collection, 1928 - [ongoing]
- Series IV: CD
  - Interview of Barbara Wriston by John Driscoll, CD 14
    Discusses her father, Henry M. Wriston.
  - Wesleyan Sings! 1928-1962, CD 15
    Wesleyan University Glee Club, Jibers, and Cardinals singing groups. See also TW97 and AC8. 1 duplicate.
  - Sir Charles P. Snow, Recent Thoughts on the Two Cultures, December 1961, CD 16
    Master and listening copy available. See also TW 51.
  - 1963 Summer School (very light) concert, CD 17a-b
    Master and listening copy available (2 discs each). See also TW 125a-c and AC20a-b.
  - Commencement, 1958: Alumni Sing, CD 18:
    Master and listening copy available. See also TW 2.
  - Gilbert H. Clee '35, Faculty Club Luncheon, Oct. 7, 1960, CD 19:
    Master and listening copy available. See also TW 40.
  - The College in Transition, L.O. Mink, Jr., R.A. Rosenbaum, V.W. Cochrane, Sept. 14, 1960., CD 20a-b:
    Master and listening copy available (2 discs each). See also TW 23.
  - The College in Transition, D.P. McAllester, W.M. Wallace, R.K. Winslow, Sept. 14, 1960., CD 21a-b:
    Master and listening copy available (2 discs each). See also TW 22.
  - V.L. Butterfield, Julian D. Anthony '28: 125th Anniversary of Phi Nu Theta (Eclectic), Oct. 27, 1962, CD 22:
    Master and listening copy available. See also TW 30.
  - Commencement, June 7, 1959, CD 23a-b:
    Master and listening copy available (2 discs each). See also TW 3.
  - The College in Transition, Eugene O. Golob, Norman O. Brown, Sept. 14, 1960., CD 24a-b:
    Master and listening copy available (2 discs each). See also TW 21.
  - V.L. Butterfield at Faculty Meeting, Dec 13, 1955?, CD 25:
    Master and listening copy available. See also TW 32.
  - The New Group Presents Boxing the Beat, 2007, CD 26:
  - The New Group, Red Light District, CD 27:
  - The New Group, Blasting Through October, 1995, CD 28:
  - The Jibers, 1957, CD 29:
    CD made by Ted Voss from original record album. The Jibers in 1957 consisted of John Allen (class of 1957), bass; David Van Norman (class of 1957), baritone; John Hall (class of 1958), 2nd tenor; and Ted Voss (class of 1957), 1st tenor. The Jibers were directed by faculty member Ray Rendall.
  - Quasimodal, eleven to one, undated, CD 30:
  - Quasimodal, Toe Up, 2002, CD 31:
  - Quasimodal, Antics, 2004, CD 32:
  - Quasimodal '07, Mobius Trip, 2007, CD 33:
  - WESU midnight news and Butterfield comment by Marjorie Daltry, day of VLB’s death, Nov. 19, 1975, CD 34:
    See also TW 84.
  - 1888 Wesleyan Glee Club at their 40th Reunion, CD 35:
  - Wesleyan Glee Club on Brunswick Records, CD 36:
- Series V: Oversize
  - Etherington Resignation [TW 77], Feb. 7, 1969, OS 1 (Box 1)
  - Etherington Office Vigil [TW 78], May 5, 1969, OS 2
  - Open Line – Coeducation at Wesleyan University [TW 80}, Dec. 12, 1971, OS 3
  - National Student Strike: The Three Demands And Wesleyan University [TW 94], May 10, 1970, OS 4
  - Welcome Back to Wesleyan, Reunion Weekend 1995 highlights tape, 3/4" reel-to-reel videotape master., OS 5
  - Fisk Hall Siege, 1968, OS 6:
    2 reels. Also listed as TW79.
    - The Grateful Dead, Live at Wesleyan, May 3, 1970, OS 7a-c:
      See also DVD 8 for viewing copy, and VTW 53d for VHS copy.
      - Scotch 1 inch video tape on reel [master], VTW 53a/OS 7a:
      - Sony Betacam SP, VTW 53b-c/OS 7b-c:
- Series VI: Unprocessed material
  The unprocessed material in this series consists of music disks and reel-to-reel movie films in metal canisters. Some general descriptions of this material can found in the collections file. There was no attempt to match the descriptions with the material at this time.
- Series VII: DVD
  - Jeffrey Schiff, The Library Project Symposium, Nov. 13, 2003, DVD 1: (Box 1)
    Symposium speakers include: Barbara Jones, Suzy Taraba, Andrew Curran, Barry Chernoff, and Jeffrey Schiff.
    2 discs
  - History Detectives, Episode 504, 2007, DVD 2: (Box 1)
    The history detectives investigate a silver bar, with a strange mark, from the Atocha shipwreck; a man in Portland, Oregon who may own a typewriter that belonged to famous war correspondent Ernie Pyle; and a copy of August Spies’ autobiography originally owned by Lucy Parsons, one with the only known copy with her stamp on the front, currently housed in the Special Collections and Archives library of Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut. Parsons sold this book to raise money to defend her husband, Albert Parsons, who was in jail, accused of participating in the Haymarket Tragedy in Chicago in 1886. Albert Parsons and August Spies were both executed, although there was no evidence to support the accusations. The Haymarket is an important milestone in labor history and the history of radical political movements.
  - Face Forward, February 2006, DVD 3: (Box 1)
    Film about African-American students at Wesleyan by Jane Charles-Voltaire (class of 2007) and Simone L. Collins (class of 2007).
    Face Forward is a short photo essay that explores Black identity and community at Wesleyan.
    It was designed to start a conversation about community and what it really means to be a Black community. Too often, the term community can be restrictive and at Wesleyan, there often is a sense of disjointedness within the Black community. The central issue was that while individuals identified themselves as being Black, that didn’t necessarily mean that they were the same. So, in many ways, the focus of this project was to show the many faces of Blackness and how we all fit together at Wesleyan.
    Methodology:
    To better understand our own Black community, specifically who we are and where we came from, we chose to interview and photograph approximately 50 Wesleyan students, each of whom identifies as Black. These students represented a multitude of backgrounds, nationalities, interests and majors. We sought to understand their Black identity as relative to others but perhaps also figure out how each of these unique identities could come together to form a new understanding of Blackness and ultimately, a community.
    We also wanted to consider the fact that we are all part of a much larger Wesleyan community and visually reference the legacy we have been left with from previous generations of Black students. The historical photographs are of Wesleyan students in the 1960's and 1970’s.
  - Stephen Crites Memorial, October 5, 2007, DVD 4: (Box 1)
  - Kay Butterfield Memorial Service, October 7, 2008, DVD 5: (Box 1)
  - Legacy and Impact: Selections from the work of Ronald K. Brown/Evidence, DVD 6: (Box 1)
    Class of 2011 Common Reading Program, presented by First Year Matters/Center for the Arts/Department of Dance.
  - Commencement 1996, Topher Bellavia speech, class of 1996, DVD 7: (Box 1)
    DVD created from VTW 10.
  - The Grateful Dead, Live at Wesleyan, May 3, 1970, DVD 8a-b:
    DVDs (master copy and viewing copy) created from videotape (VTW 53).
  - Wesleyan Commencement, 1993, DVD 9a-b:
    DVDs (master copy and viewing copy) created from video.
- Series VIII: Record Albums
  - The Wesleyan Jibers in College Songs and Barber Shop, 1943
    2 copies. 78 rpm format. See also AC18.